careeronestop.org 2003-06-04

# CareerOneStop - Privacy Statement

Privacy and Security Statement  
  
Thank you for visiting the CareerOneStop Website and reviewing our privacy and security statement. CareerOneStop is strongly committed to maintaining the privacy of your personal information and the security of our computer systems. With respect to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information, CareerOneStop makes every effort to ensure compliance with applicable Federal law, including, but not limited to, the Privacy Act of 1974, the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1995, and the Freedom of Information Act.   
As a general rule, the CareerOneStop does not collect personally-identifying information about you when you visit our site, unless you choose to provide such information to us. The information we receive depends upon what you do when visiting our site.   
   
_If you visit our site to read or download information, we collect and store the following information:_

  * The name of the domain from which you access the Internet.
  * The date and time you access our site. 
  * The Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site.

The above information is used by software programs on our website to create summary statistics which allow us to assess the number of visitors to the different sections of our site, identify what information is of most and least interest, determine technical design specifications, monitor system performance, and help us make our site more useful to visitors.   
   
_If you identify yourself by sending an E-mail containing personal information:_  
   
You also may decide to send us personally-identifying information, for example your mailing address, in an electronic mail message requesting that information be mailed to you. Information collected in this manner is used solely for responding to requests for information or records. We may forward your E-mail to other Government employees who are better able to respond to you. Should you wish to file a request under FOIA, instructions are provided at: <http://www.careeronestop.org/usersupport/UserSupport.asp>  
   
_If you link to other sites outside CareerOneStop:_  
   
Our Website has many links to other sites. When you link to any of these sites, you are no longer on our site and are subject to the privacy policy of the new site.   
   
_Cookie Use Notice_  
   
On a limited number of its web pages, the CareerOneStop employs "cookies" to provide better service to its customers. The CareerOneStop does not use cookies to collect any personally identifying information from users or to track user activities beyond our web site. The CareerOneStop does not maintain copies of cookies on our web site after you leave our web site.   
   
Cookies are small pieces of temporary data that are exchanged between a web site and a user's computer which enable a "session", or "dialog", to be established between the two machines. With the session established, the CareerOneStop is able to tailor its responses (i.e., identify and provide you with the information you want) and help you traverse our web pages in the most efficient and effective manner possible. The session is often broken when the CareerOneStop server does not receive further requests from your computer or you simply exit your browser.   
   
The CareerOneStop limits its use of cookies to "session cookies"... types of cookies that are temporarily stored in your computer's memory. Session cookies are normally deleted from a user's computer when the user logs off the computer or the user exits the browser. The CareerOneStop does not issue "persistent cookies"…types of cookies that could be stored permanently on your workstation and reused each time you visit the CareerOneStop web site.   

* * *  

For security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, our website also employs software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage.   
   
Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act of 1996
